[MUSIC]
[موسيقى]
>> Let's now explore in more depth that learning task of learning decision tree.
>> دعونا نتعمق أكثر الآن في مهمة التعلم المتعلقة بشجرة القرارات.
So just like before we're giving a set of training data, and
لذا، فقبل أن نبدأ في تقديم مجموعة من بيانات التدريب
we extract some features from that.
ونستخرج بعض السمات من ذلك.
And then we're going to take this decision tree model, T of x, and
ثم نأخذ بعد ذلك نموذج شجرة القرارات (T(x،
use it to predict y hat.
واستخدامه للتنبؤ بالقيمة Y^.
So let's explore the T of x in a little bit more detail and
لذا، لنستكشف (T(x بالمزيد من التفصيل
discuss what the learning process might look like here.
ونناقش ما قد تبدو عليه عملية التعلم هنا.
In particular we're given a data set here, which is a table where each row
وعلى وجه الخصوص، فإن لدينا مجموعة من البيانات هنا، وهي عبارة عن جدول حيث كل صف
corresponds to a data point, and we have our features here,
يتوافق مع أحد نقاط البيانات، ولدينا بعض السمات هنا،
h1 of x, h2 of x, h3 of x.
(h1(x و(h2(x و(h3(x.
So credit, term, and income, so in this example it's only going to be three
والتي تمثل الائتمان والفترة والدخل، لذا، في هذا المثال سيكون لدينا ثلاث سمات فقط،
features, and then when try to predict a, what we call, loan status.
ثم نحاول التنبؤ بما ندعوه بحالة القرض.
Which is this variable y, which is whether the loan is risky or safe.
والتي تمثل المتغير y، والذي يشير إلى ما إذا كان القرض خطير أو آمن.
And our goal is to learn the decision tree that can help us make that prediction.
هدفنا هو التعرف إلى شجرة القرارات التي يمكن أن تساعدنا في القيام بعملية التنبؤ،
Given one or more of these input features.
بالنسبة لواحدة أو أكثر من سمات الإدخال هذه.
More generally we're going to be given N observations from our data of the form xi,
وبشكل أعم، سيكون لدينا عملية المراقبة N من البيانات لدينا للشكل xi
yi where yi is the true label.
وyi حيث أن yi تكون التسمية الحقيقية.
And, we're trying to optimize some kind of a quality metric that tries to fit
ونحاول تحسين نوعًا من قياس الجودة الذي يتناسب مع
a tree that is as good as possible with respect to that metric.
الشجرة التي تكون جيدة قدر الإمكان فيما يتعلق بهذا المقياس.
And, in the case of the decision trees the metrics we're going to use
وفي حالة شجرة القرارات، فإن المقياس الذي سنستخدمه
Is just straight up classification error.
هو بشكل مباشر عبارة عن خطأ بالتصنيف.
There are other metrics that you may use for decision trees, but just for
وهناك مقاييس أخرى يمكن استخدامها بالنسبة لشجرة القرارات، ولكن
this module we just want to focus straight up on classification error.
في هذه الوحدة سنركز بشكل مباشر على الخطأ في التصنيف.
And classification error measures the fraction of mistakes that we make
ويقوم مقياس الخطأ في التصنيف بقياس نسبة الأخطاء التي نقوم بها
when we try to make prediction of the trailing data.
عندما نحاول القيام بعملية تنبؤ بشأن بيانات التدريب.
So that's the number of incorrect predictions divided by the total number of
لذا، فهي عبارة عن عدد التنبؤات الخاطئة مقسومًا على العدد الإجمالي
examples, just like we saw.
للأمثلة، تمامًا كما رأينا
In the logistic regression case.
في حالة الانحدار اللوجستي.
The best possible value here is 0, no mistakes,
وأفضل قيمة محتملة هنا هي 0، وتعني أنه لا توجد أخطاء،
and the worst possible value here is 1.
وأسوأ قيمة محتملة هنا هي 1.
I made as many mistakes as there are data points.
وقد وضعت أكبر عدد ممكن من الأخطاء في نقطة البيانات.
So hopefully you don't have error 1, hopefully you have error closer to 0.
لذا، لنأمل ألا تحصلوا خطأ بالقيمة 1، وان تحصلوا على نسبة خطأ قيمة أقرب إلى 0.
So now that we've seen classification error,
والآن بما أننا قد رأينا، مقياس الخطأ في التصنيف،
we can state more clearly where our learning goal is.
يمكننا تحديد أهداف التعلم لدينا بشكل أكثر وضوحًا.
Given the dataset, find the tree that minimizes the classification error.
وفقًا لمجموعة البيانات الموجودة، يمكننا العثور على الشجرة التي تقوم بتقليل نسبة الخطأ في التصنيف.
The question is, how hard is this problem?
والسؤال هو، ما مدى صعوبة هذه المشكلة؟
How hard is this learning task?
ما مدى صعوبة مهمة التعلم هذه؟
And it turns out that this is an extremely hard learning task.
وقد اتضح أن هذه مهمة تعلم صعبة للغاية.
There's exponentially many combination of decision trees out there.
وهناك تركيبات كثيرة لأشجار القرارات هناك.
Even if you consider just one branch of decision tree.
حتى إذا نظرت فقط إلى فرع واحد في شجرة القرارات.
Selecting what features to come next in an order can be a really hard problem and
يمكن أن تكون عملية تحديد السمات التي ستأتي لاحقًا في ترتيب ما، هي مشكلة صعبة للغاية
lead to explanation in many combinations.
والتي تؤدي إلى كم هائل من التركيبات.
And in fact, for
وفي الواقع،
those familiar with this, this is an example what's called an NP hard problem.
بالنسبة لأولئك المطلعين على ذلك، فإن هذا مثال على ما يسمى بمشكلة NP الصعبة للغاية.
So, it's a really hard problem and there are no approximation algorithms for
لذا، فهذه مشكلة صعبة للغاية، لا توجد أي خوارزميات تقريبية لهذه المشكلة
this problem with guarantees, but there is some simple ideas of heuristics
مع ضمانات، ولكن هناك بعض الأفكار البسيطة حول الاستدلال
that tend to perform extremely well in practice.
والتي تميل إلى الأداء بشكل جيد للغاية فيما يتعلق بالممارسة.
And we're going to talk about one such idea today,
وسنتحدث عن فكرة واحدة اليوم،
Wwhich is called the greedy, simple greedy algorithm, basically.
والتي تدعى في الواقع بخوارزمية greedy البسيطة.
And we're going to incrementally build a tree, one layer at a time,
وسنقوم ببناء الشجرة تدريجيًا، حيث سنضع طبقة واحدة في كل مرة،
in order to get the best possible classification error at each step.
بهدف الحصول على أفضل قيمة ممكنة لنسبة الخطأ في التصنيف بكل خطوة.
>> [MUSIC]
>> [موسيقى]